<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: inspiration | Justin T Stanley]]></title>
  <link href="http://justintstanley.com/blog/categories/inspiration/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://justintstanley.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-12T14:04:10-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://justintstanley.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Justin Stanley]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sweet Defiance]]></title>
    <link href="http://justintstanley.com/blog/2014/02/12/sweet-defiance/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-12T13:01:27-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://justintstanley.com/blog/2014/02/12/sweet-defiance</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The recent buzz over CandyCrush maker King applying for a trademark on the word “Candy” has prompted a newer form of protest, a game jam. While the outrage seems to stem from a misunderstanding of trademark law and its uses, the #CandyJam is full steam ahead, with 29 games submitted at the time of this writing.</p>

<p>Trademark filings are by no means the same as actually receiving the trademark. From a business and intellectual property standpoint King is making a smart move. The CandyCrush Saga is a multimillion dollar tasty piece of intellectual property and the company deserved to reap the rewards from its hard work, level design, and obvious skill. However, the game is a knockoff. It’s a well done knockoff, but clearly it’s a tweaked version of Bejeweled. Of course Bejeweled is a tweaked knockoff too, of Tetris, SameGame, and Dr. Mario, but in internet time it’s the grand ole man of tile matching games, despite only being published in 2001.</p>

<p>In the ancient times of yore Bejeweled wasn’t the actually named Bejeweled. Instead it was called Diamond Mine. Microsoft suggested Bejeweled to eliminate possible confusion with an existing game Diamond Mines.</p>

<p>Similar game names isn’t a new problem and as I stated above, King is making the right business move. The jury is still out on if the application is too broad, I’m not a lawyer so who knows, but the reaction of the game developer crowd does highlight several potential problems in too big a broom.</p>

<p>Still, I think the reaction is a positive one. Instead of other, more malicious means of protest, people are doing something creative. Using frustration as a spark the #CandyJam is at least on the right track. Let people have their cake and eat it too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
